<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>doc.flashduty.com</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</lastBuildDate><item><title>Flashduty ⋅ Alert Response Platform</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/start/overview.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Flashduty, <strong>an enterprise-level one-stop alert response platform</strong>. We help developers, DevOps, operations, and business leaders speed up alert response, improve product experience, and reduce incident losses.</h2><h1 style="display:flex;justify-content:space-between" id="H0">Flashduty ⋅ Alert Response Platform<img src="https://fc.3ti.site/i.svg" style="user-select:none;margin-top:-1px;width:42px"></h1><h2>What is Flashduty?</h2><p>Flashduty, <strong>an enterprise-level one-stop alert response platform</strong>.</p><p>We help developers, DevOps, operations, and business leaders speed up alert response, improve product experience, and reduce incident losses.</p><h3>Key Features</h3><ol><li><strong>Centralized Alert Handling</strong>: Supports integration with most monitoring systems, providing a single platform for noise reduction, dispatch, collaboration, and automation of all alerts</li><li><strong>Never Miss Critical Alerts</strong>: Supports flexible on-call and scheduling strategies, ensuring alerts are only dispatched to the right personnel, with automatic escalation after timeouts and multi-channel notifications to avoid missing alerts</li><li><strong>No More Alert Storms</strong>: Achieves up to 90% alert noise reduction, effectively managing alert storms and flapping scenarios, and preventing alert fatigue among development teams.</li><li><strong>IM System Alert Handling</strong>: Supports handling alerts within Feishu, DingTalk, Enterprise WeChat, Slack, and Teams, ensuring multi-end synchronization and more efficient collaboration.</li><li><strong>Observable Incident Handling</strong>: Establishes multi-dimensional analysis metrics for processing efficiency, driving continuous reduction in incident resolution times.</li></ol><h2>Why Choose Flashduty?</h2><ol><li><strong>User Experience First</strong>: Provides a simple and intuitive interface, balancing ease of use with flexibility.</li><li><strong>Powerful Features</strong>: Rich integrations, high scalability, and API-first approach. Offers solutions for various scenarios.</li><li><strong>Rapid Iteration</strong>: Receives real feedback from thousands of enterprise users in the Nightingale open-source community, enabling rapid iteration.</li><li><strong>High Cost-Effectiveness</strong>: Offers reasonable pricing and excellent customer service.</li></ol><h2>How to Contact Us?</h2><p><strong>Scan the QR code to add technical support enterprise WeChat to get technical support</strong>:</p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/start/overview/1.avif" alt="drawing" width="200"><p><strong>Scan the QR code to add the business manager’s enterprise WeChat to get business support</strong>:</p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/start/overview/2.avif" alt="drawing" width="200"><p><strong>Console Feedback</strong>:</p><p>Log in to the console, go to the top right corner, and visit <strong>Support =&gt; Feedback</strong> to submit your feedback.</p><p><strong>Send us an email</strong>:
<a href="mailto:contact-us@flashcat.cloud">contact-us@flashcat.cloud</a></p><h2>Try It Now!</h2><p>Visit <a href="https://console.flashcat.cloud/login?from=docs-intro">the console</a>, complete registration, and receive 14 days of free trial. Try it now!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/start/getting_started.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Learn how to get started quickly with Flashduty</h2><h1>Quick Start</h1><h2>Demo Video</h2><p><video poster="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/start/getting_started/3.avif" controls src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/start/getting_started/4.mp4"></video></p><h2>Start for Free</h2><ol><li>Visit the <a href="https://console.flashcat.cloud/">Flashduty Console</a> with your browser, enter your <strong>mobile phone number</strong> or <strong>work email</strong>, read and agree to our <a href="/license/user">Terms of Service</a> and <a href="/license/privacy_policy">Privacy Policy</a>, click Next, and the system will send a verification code to your mobile phone or email.</li><li>Enter the name of your <strong>company or organization</strong> and the verification code obtained in the previous step, click Next to complete the registration.</li><li>The system will guide you through completing your information and will send you a custom alert event to experience voice, text message, or email alerts.</li></ol><blockquote><p>[!NOTE]
For security reasons, the system only allows registration through a work email. This means that if you use an email address with a suffix such as qq.com, gmail.com, 163.com, etc., you will be refused registration.</p></blockquote><h2>Basic Process</h2><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/start/getting_started/2.avif" alt="" /></p><h3>Create a Collaboration Space</h3><p>A collaboration space is a container for related incidents. We generally create a collaboration space based on the services owned, managed, and monitored by a team, such as order systems, recommendation services, MySQL components, Client A, etc.</p><p>Enter the <a href="https://console.flashcat.cloud/channel">Collaboration Space</a> list page, click <strong>Create Collaboration Space</strong>, enter an intuitive and concise name and description. Associate a management team with the collaboration space to facilitate future multi-person management.</p><blockquote><p>[!WARN]
Collaboration spaces are managed using data permissions rather than role-based controls.</p><p><strong>Only the account owner, collaboration space creator, and management team members</strong> have the permission to modify the configuration of the collaboration space. Others can only view it. This means that anyone can create a collaboration space, but can only modify the collaboration spaces they manage.</p><p><strong>Even if you are an account administrator, you cannot modify the configuration of collaboration spaces that you do not manage.</strong></p></blockquote><h3>Integrate Alert Events</h3><p>The collaboration space can only store incidents. To receive alert event reports, we need to introduce external integrations.</p><ol><li>Enter the collaboration space details, click <strong>Integrate Data</strong>, choose <strong>Add an Integration</strong>, select the alert system used by your company, and save.</li><li>The new integration will generate an independent push address. Any alerts reported to this address will directly enter the current collaboration space. You need to complete the alert push configuration according to the documentation in the integration details.</li></ol><ul><li>Want to deliver alerts to different collaboration spaces based on conditions? Go to <strong>Integration Center - Alert Events</strong>, add a shared integration, and set routing rules based on conditions. This method is especially suitable for integrations like Zabbix and Prometheus, where it is inconvenient to manage push webhooks by policy.</li></ul><ol start="3"><li>If this integration receives an alert event, the integration card will display <strong>the latest event time</strong>; otherwise, it will display <strong>no alert events received yet</strong>. You can check whether the monitoring system has generated new alerts and whether the network is normal.</li></ol><blockquote><p>[!NOTE]
Flashduty has already adapted to most commonly used monitoring systems, allowing you to use it out of the box. If you have a self-developed alert system, please use <strong>Custom Events</strong> or <strong>Email Integration</strong>. If you have other monitoring system requirements, feel free to contact us.</p></blockquote><h3>Configure Notification Methods</h3><p>When an incident occurs, how will you be notified?</p><ol><li>Enter the collaboration space details, click <strong>Dispatch Strategy</strong>, and add or modify the dispatch strategy.</li><li>Enter step 1 configuration, specify the dispatch personnel, i.e., the responders after the incident is triggered. Specify the notification methods for the assigned personnel.</li></ol><ul><li>Select a shift, team, or individual as the dispatch target. We recommend using shifts. When an incident is triggered, the system will only notify the current on-duty personnel.</li><li>Single chat means one-to-one notification, such as text message, voice, email, etc. IM applications like Feishu and DingTalk also support one-to-one chat push.</li><li>Group chat means pushing to an IM message group and @-mentioning the assigned personnel.</li></ul><ol start="4"><li>To ensure that someone handles the incident, you can add an escalation step. For example, if the incident is not resolved within 30 minutes, it will be escalated to the Team Leader.</li></ol><blockquote><p>[!NOTE]
How to configure incident notifications according to personal preferences?
Go to the <strong>Account Settings =&gt; Notification Settings</strong> page to set how you are notified when you are assigned and when duty rotation occurs. Note that this setting only takes effect when dispatching directly or dispatching by policy and specifying personal preferences.</p></blockquote><h2>Official Subscription</h2><blockquote><p>[!NOTE]
People with <strong>subscription management</strong> rights can perform this action.</p></blockquote><p>Newly registered businesses will automatically receive a 2-week free trial. After the trial, you can go to the <strong>Billing Center</strong> and choose the Professional or Standard Edition to upgrade.</p><ul><li>You can compare the functional differences between different versions at the bottom of the page.</li><li>Only members who handle daily incidents need a license. If you only passively receive alert notifications, you do not need to purchase a license.</li><li>If the license is insufficient, members without a license cannot view or handle incidents. You can go to the console to purchase additional licenses at any time, which will take effect immediately.</li><li>Each license includes a certain amount of free communication quota, which is shared among all members.</li><li>Five days before the subscription expires, the system will send a daily reminder via text message to the main account. Please renew in time to avoid affecting alert reception.</li></ul>]]></description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/start/frequently_asked_questions.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Learn about the most common issues when using Flashduty</h2><h1>Frequently Asked Questions</h1><p>|+| What is Flashduty?</p><pre><code>Flashduty is a one-stop alert response platform. We provide IT professionals with on-call, alert noise reduction, escalation, and automation capabilities to accelerate enterprise incident response and minimize losses.
</code></pre><p>|+| Am I a good fit for Flashduty?</p><pre><code>You should use Flashduty if your organization or team:

- Needs a centralized place to collect alerts from all sources within the company, and to process, track, and analyze them uniformly.
- Needs to prioritize alerts and notify key personnel dynamically through different channels, and automate the escalation process to avoid unattended alerts.
- Spends most of its energy on daily alert processing and needs alert noise reduction to address alert fatigue.
</code></pre><p>|+| What notification methods does Flashduty support?</p><pre><code>| Channels |  Private chat  | Group chat |
| --- | -------- | ---- |
| Voice    | ✅   |    |
| SMS    | ✅   |    |
| Email    | ✅   |    |
| Feishu Application | ✅   |  ✅  |
| DingTalk Application | ✅   |  ✅  |
| WeChat Work application | ✅   |    |
| Slack Application| ✅   |  ✅  |
| Microsoft Teams Application| ✅   |  ✅  |
| Feishu Robot only supports sending plain text messages    |    |  ✅  |
| DingTalk Robot    |    |  ✅  |
| WeChat Work bot    |    |  ✅  |
| Zoom Bot    |    |  ✅  |
| Telegram Bot    |    |  ✅  |
</code></pre><p>|+| Does Flashduty use a fixed number for voice notifications?</p><pre><code>- Mainland China: **( 010 ) 21364727** and **( 021 ) 3201 7538** , more numbers can download and import the link file to your phone: [http://donwloads.flashcat.cloud/phone.vcf](http://donwloads.flashcat.cloud/phone.vcf)
- United States, Canada: **12087959989**
- Indonesia, Germany, Malaysia, Australia, Singapore, Thailand, Russia, South Korea, Saudi Arabia, Vietnam, Japan, Hong Kong, Taiwan: **Random number**
- Other regions do not currently support voice notifications. If you have a need, please contact us: contact-us@flashcat.cloud
</code></pre><p>|+| How can I ensure Flashduty notifies me?</p><pre><code>Flashduty strives to ensure the availability of every channel.

- Voice, SMS, and email: We use high-availability services provided by multiple cloud vendors and can quickly switch to another if one fails.
- IM application messages: If the IM application single chat message fails to send, the system will use SMS and email as a fallback.
- Dispatch policy settings: It is recommended to set up circular notifications. If the incident is not claimed, the system will loop through multiple notifications. Or set up an escalation process. If the person in the current step does not handle it in time, the incident will be escalated to the next step.
</code></pre><p>|+| Why can't I receive voice notifications?</p><pre><code>Voice calls depend heavily on the terminal signal and settings. If you consistently cannot receive voice notifications, it is recommended to try the following operations:

1. If you are using a mobile phone number registered outside mainland China, please check the geographical range we support.
2. First, check the phone's blacklist or call history to see if numbers around the time of the call were blocked, usually fixed-line numbers such as 010xxx or 021xx. If so, remove the number from the blacklist and add it to the whitelist.
3. If the phone does not show the number in the blacklist, it may be that the phone number has activated interception services or similar features: For mobile numbers, you can check if incoming landline calls were blocked through the WeChat official account &quot;China Mobile High-Frequency Harassment Call Protection&quot;; for telecom numbers, you can check through the official account &quot;Tianyi Anti-Harassment&quot;; for China Unicom, you can check through the official account &quot;Wo Assistant&quot; or contact customer service.
4. Please note that if your phone number has been ported, you should check the blocking status with multiple operators.
5. Try restarting the phone, reinserting the SIM card, and inserting the SIM card into another phone to troubleshoot terminal or SIM card issues

If you still cannot find the reason, please contact us.
</code></pre><p>|+| Why can't I receive email notifications?</p><pre><code>It is recommended to try the following:

1. Check the spam folder in your email client. If the email is there, move it to the inbox to maintain normal reception
2. Check if the email client is set to automatically delete emails. If so, modify the settings
3. Contact your company's corporate email administrator and check if the email was blocked in the backend (corporate email systems like Gmail have strict restrictions, and sending too many emails can lead to blocking). If so, set up a whitelist for the email source.

If you still cannot find the reason, please contact us.
</code></pre><p>|+| Can Flashduty set routing for alert fields?</p><pre><code>Yes, Flashduty supports matching alert events based on multiple dimensions such as labels, severity, titles, and descriptions, and routing them to different collaboration spaces. For details, see Integration Center - Integration Details - Routing Configuration.
</code></pre><p>|+| What alert systems does Flashduty support?</p><pre><code>- Universal integration: email alerts (almost applicable to all alert systems); custom event standards (for self-developed monitoring systems).
- Open-source integration: Zabbix, Prometheus, Nightingale, and other common open-source monitoring systems.
- Commercial integration: Alibaba Cloud, Tencent Cloud, Huawei Cloud, AWS, Azure, and other commercial cloud monitoring systems.

If you have other needs, feel free to contact us.
</code></pre><p>|+| How does Flashduty charge?</p><pre><code>We charge according to active users and provide three different versions: free version, standard version and commercial version. For detailed comparison, please visit: https://flashcat.cloud/flashduty/price/

- We define users who use commercial features in the current month as active users, and these users must obtain a license to use the service.
- At the end of each monthly cycle, the licenses held by active users will be released and must be reacquired in the next cycle.
- When a member is deleted, their license is automatically released.
- Viewing alerts requires a license, but passively receiving notifications does not.
</code></pre><p>|+| How does Flashduty ensure its stability?</p><pre><code>-  Flashduty SLA:

1. Functional availability: Ensure that core functions are available 99.95% of the time
2. Delivery timeliness: Ensure that 99.95% of alerts are delivered within 5 minutes after being triggered

-  How Flashduty ensures SLA:

1. Multi-active in the same city: The infrastructure is built on multiple data centers, and stateful components are multi-active in the same city
2. Asynchronous processing: After an alert is reported, it immediately enters an asynchronous process with retries to reduce the risk of alert loss
3. Redundant alerts: For important alerts, a redundant notification mechanism is provided. Customers can choose multiple channels to ensure notifications are received
4. Global acceleration: Global acceleration has been enabled for the api.flashcat.cloud domain name to ensure stable reporting links in various locations;
5. Continuous monitoring: Comprehensive collection of system metrics, regular stress testing, and timely or preemptive discovery of system issues.
</code></pre><p>|+| How does Flashduty ensure data security?</p><pre><code>1. Full-stack HTTPS ensures secure data transmission
2. Sensitive information is encrypted and stored, and logs are desensitized before being written to disk
3. Important data modifications require MFA verification and support operation auditing
4. Regular participation in third-party security certification audits by internationally and domestically recognized organizations (ISO27001, ISO9001)
5. For customers with specific needs, a confidentiality agreement can be signed
6. Privacy Agreement: https://docs.flashcat.cloud/docs/privacy-policy
</code></pre><p>|+| Does Flashduty support private deployment?</p><pre><code>Yes, Flashduty provides a private deployment version that is almost identical to the SaaS service. However, due to the high maintenance costs, the pricing model for private deployment is different from that of SaaS services. If not necessary, we recommend using cloud services.

If you need a private version, please contact us.
</code></pre><p>|+| What advantages does Flashduty have over other platforms?</p><pre><code>1. We provide more flexible and user-friendly features
2. We offer more professional and considerate services
3. We provide more reasonable product pricing

Feel free to contact us to get a professional purchasing guide.
</code></pre>]]></description></item><item><title>Product Comparison</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/start/comparison_to_alternatives.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Compare Flashduty and Pagerduty Products, Services, and Prices</h2><h1>Product Comparison</h1><h3>Preface</h3><p>In today's rapidly changing IT environment, organizations increasingly rely on a comprehensive suite of monitoring and incident management tools to ensure business continuity and service stability. However, as monitoring systems continue to expand, a massive number of alerts and event notifications are generated, presenting unprecedented challenges to IT teams. Ensuring that every alert is captured in a timely manner, delivered accurately, and responded to effectively has become a critical factor in maintaining service quality.</p><p>Faced with this challenge, we have identified the following scenarios that indicate organizations need to introduce or upgrade their On-Call tools:</p><ul><li><strong>Comprehensive Tracking and Resolution</strong>: Ensure that every incident can be tracked, processed, and resolved to prevent the problem from escalating and thereby avoid greater asset losses.</li><li><strong>Establishment of a Duty Mechanism</strong>: Establish a clear On-Call personnel duty mechanism, including a primary and backup shift system, to reasonably distribute responsibilities and avoid alert overload.</li><li><strong>Improving Response Efficiency</strong>: When SRE or R&amp;D personnel spend more than 25% of their time on On-Call duties, tools are needed to reduce noise and improve work efficiency.</li><li><strong>Establishment of Quantitative Metrics</strong>: Establish metrics for incident processing timeliness and personnel workload to drive continuous improvement in service stability through data.</li></ul><p><strong>&quot;What key factors should we consider when purchasing On-Call services?&quot;</strong> This guide will provide comprehensive On-Call tool purchasing recommendations. We will examine the three dimensions of <strong>product</strong>, <strong>service</strong>, and <strong>price</strong> to explore the questions IT managers should ask when seeking efficient collaboration and incident management solutions for their development and operations teams. Additionally, for each dimension, we will provide a comparative analysis of mainstream domestic and international On-Call suppliers such as Flashduty and Pagerduty to help you make an informed decision.</p><h3>Product</h3><h4>Integration Capabilities</h4><p>The incident management system serves as a process handling center, storing all alert and incident data. Such systems should support robust data access and outbound call capabilities to integrate with other systems or workflows, accelerating response times and enhancing collaboration.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Product Capabilities</th><th>Questions to Consider</th><th>Flashduty vs. Pagerduty</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Alert Integration</strong></td><td>1.  Does it support your commonly used alert system? <br> 2. Does it support custom alert integration? Can it report self-developed script monitoring data through standard protocols? <br> 3. Does it support email integration? Can incidents be triggered or closed via email? <br> 4. Does it support change-related integrations? <br> Incidents are generally caused by changes, and integrating change processes can help quickly troubleshoot. <br> 5. Is the integration documentation easy to find and clearly written? <br> Can you complete the configuration based on the documentation by yourself?</td><td>Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Pagerduty supports most overseas monitoring tools. <br> Flashduty supports domestic and international mainstream monitoring tools and also supports the Pagerduty protocol, allowing some tools to directly push data to Flashduty in Pagerduty mode.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Webhooks</strong></td><td>1.  Does it support incident operation external push Webhook? To integrate with self-developed processes or tools? <br> 2. Does it support subscription for event types or sources? For example, can you subscribe to dispatch events for a specific order system?</td><td>Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Open APIs</strong></td><td>Does it support a rich Open API that allows customers to operate data entities through the API?</td><td>Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Both provide rich APIs and documentation.</td></tr></tbody></table><h4>Incident Handling</h4><p>Incident handling is the core operation of the system. This dimension primarily evaluates the <strong>richness</strong> and <strong>flexibility</strong> of product features.</p><table><thead><tr><th align="center">Product Capabilities</th><th align="left">Questions to Consider</th><th align="left">Flashduty vs. Pagerduty</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center"><strong>Alert Routing</strong></td><td align="left">1.  Does it support proprietary integrations? <br> Can you route directly to services or collaboration spaces without additional routing? <br> 2. Does it support shared integrations? And flexible routing rules?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Pagerduty only supports shared integration keys and does not have a shared integration concept. Flashduty can set routing rules on the integration page, while Pagerduty requires complex Event Orchestration or Workflow to achieve this.</td></tr><tr><td align="center"><strong>Information Enhancement</strong></td><td align="left">Does it support setting custom fields? <br> Can you add fields, define types and enumeration values, and expand incident information?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support extracting new tags from existing information using regular expressions? <br> e.g., extracting data center information from hostnames</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support combining new tags from existing information? <br> e.g., generating a runbook URL from service and alert policies</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support importing data tables to dynamically generate new labels? <br> e.g., importing CMDB data to generate owner information based on host IP</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌ <br> Flashduty supports flexible data mapping schemes.</td></tr><tr><td align="center"><strong>Alert Noise Reduction</strong></td><td align="left">Does it support aggregating alerts into incidents? <br> 1. Can it aggregate similar alerts for dispatch, notification, and handling to improve efficiency and reduce alert fatigue? <br> 2. Does it support aggregating incidents based on time windows? <br> 3. Does it support merging based on AI?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Pagerduty supports <strong>intelligent aggregation</strong> and <strong>policy aggregation</strong>. <br> Flashduty supports <strong>fine-grained control policy aggregation</strong>.</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support incident suppression? <br> Can it stop alerts during market closure or system maintenance?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support incident suppression? <br> For example, if an incident occurs on a host, can it suppress pod incidents?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support storm warnings? <br> When the number of aggregated alert incidents is too high, can it notify to increase response efforts?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support incident jitter convergence? <br> If the same incident occurs frequently and is quickly resolved, can it reduce notifications to avoid wasting resources?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support delayed incident notifications? <br> Can it delay notifications for a window to filter out incidents that are automatically resolved immediately, reducing resource waste?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"><strong>Incident Dispatch</strong></td><td align="left">Does it support dispatching incidents by policy? <br> 1. Can it dispatch to shifts, teams, or individuals? <br> 2. Can it set group chat or individual chat notification methods simultaneously?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Flashduty additionally supports dispatching to teams and setting notification methods. <br> Pagerduty can only configure single chat and group chat globally and cannot match to the incident level.</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support dispatching based on conditional matching? <br> 1. Can it support multiple dispatch strategies with weighted matching?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌ <br> Pagerduty only supports one upgrade strategy per Service. <br> Flashduty supports configuring multiple dispatch strategies under a collaboration space, each of which can take effect at different times or for different incident ranges.</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support automatic incident escalation if unresolved after a timeout? <br> 1. Does it support manual escalation?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support dynamic dispatching based on parameters or tags? <br> 1. Can it dynamically replace assigned personnel based on tags to reduce system integration costs? <br> 2. Can it dynamically replace group chat information based on tags to reduce configuration maintenance costs?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"><strong>Incident Handling</strong></td><td align="left">Does it support manually creating incidents?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support incident claiming, closing, commenting, deferring, and merging? <br> 1. Does it support automatic closure after a timeout? <br> 2. Does it support automatic cancellation of deferral after a timeout?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support incident post-mortem analysis?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support similar incident identification?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support detailed operation records?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support reassigning incidents?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support adding custom operations to incidents? <br> For example, manually triggering a host restart for incident self-healing?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support reopening and notifying incidents after they are closed?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support setting custom fields? <br> For example, marking false positives or adding meeting links?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Both support multiple types of custom fields. <br> Flashduty supports searching by fields. <br> Pagerduty can only view field settings in incident details.</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it have strong search capabilities?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌ <br> Flashduty supports searching by tags, custom fields, titles, and personnel information. <br> Flashduty supports exact, wildcard, and regular expression matching. <br> Flashduty supports card view. <br> Flashduty supports custom rendering of incident list content.</td></tr><tr><td align="center"><strong>Incident Analysis</strong></td><td align="left">Does it support counting incidents and events based on dimensions such as time, team, and service?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support notifying incident processing metrics based on dimensions such as time, team, and service? <br> For example, MTTA and MTTR?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support tracking incident processing metrics for personnel? <br> For example, MTTA and the number of incidents handled?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support tracking the most frequent hosts and policies where incidents occur?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support tracking the time personnel spend handling incidents?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support custom statistical reports?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support sending statistical reports regularly?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support large-screen display of analysis boards?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td align="center"></td><td align="left">Does it support downloading detailed data?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr></tbody></table><h4>Platform Capabilities</h4><p>Platform capabilities primarily focus on member management, duty response, and notification capabilities. The system should have basic audit and single sign-on functions. The richer the notification channels, the better, and the more localized support, the better. Duty management should best meet the special scenarios within the organization.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Product Capabilities</th><th>Questions to Consider</th><th align="left">Flashduty vs. Pagerduty</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Duty Management</strong></td><td>Does it support rotation based on days, weeks, or custom cycles?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support limiting duty hours within a rotation cycle?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support different rotation rules for different time periods?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Flashduty can set the cycle end time.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support setting up temporary shift adjustments?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support setting duty roles? For example, primary and backup duty?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support multiple people on duty at the same time? Rotating together?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support fair rotation? <br> For example, if 7 people rotate daily, is it fair that one person is always on duty on Sunday?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support setting rotation notifications, including advance notifications?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Flashduty supports more notification methods</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support exporting duty calendars?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Notification Channels</strong></td><td>Does it support domestic voice and SMS?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Pagerduty <strong>limited support, unstable</strong></td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support fixed display numbers?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support email notifications?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support domestic mainstream IM application integration?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Flashduty supports: Feishu, DingTalk, and Qiwei application integration.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support integration with foreign mainstream IM applications?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Both support Slack and Microsoft Teams. <br> Flashduty additionally supports Zoom and Telegram bots.</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support mobile apps?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ❌, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr><tr><td></td><td>Does it support custom notification templates?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ❌ <br> Flashduty supports rich template syntax.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Single Sign-On</strong></td><td>Does it support single sign-on? What protocols are supported?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅ <br> Flashduty supports SAML, OIDC; <br> Pagerduty supports SAML, OAuth2</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Operational Audit</strong></td><td>Does it support operational auditing?</td><td align="left">Flashduty ✅, Pagerduty ✅</td></tr></tbody></table><h3>Price</h3><p>Vendors generally offer multiple subscription options. However, we primarily consider which one is more cost-effective when meeting our own needs. Ensuring that actual usage does not exceed the budget and the simplicity of the pricing method are important.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Comparison Items</th><th>Flashduty</th><th>Pagerduty</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Price Page</strong></td><td><a href="https://flashcat.cloud/flashduty/price/">price.flashcat.cloud</a></td><td><a href="https://www.pagerduty.com/pricing/incident-response/">price.pagerduty.com</a></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Charging Method</strong></td><td>Seat fee + excess communication fee</td><td>Seat fee + Add-Ons</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Version Distinction</strong></td><td>Professional version ￥179/person/month, full functionality</td><td>Business version $41/person/month, Add-Ons charged separately (e.g., AIops)</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Are active user fees only charged?</strong></td><td>Yes, <br> The standard for active users is members who view or process incidents in the current month. Merely receiving notifications does not count as an active user</td><td>no,<br> Process alert Need to buy Full License , only receive alert need to buy Stakeholder License package, 50 minimum selling, each $3/ person / month</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Free Trial</strong></td><td>Pro version offers a 14-day free trial, <br> and an additional 14 days are granted after completing the configuration, totaling 28 days</td><td>Business version offers a 14-day free trial</td></tr></tbody></table><h3>Service</h3><p>The service dimension primarily evaluates the supplier's service response methods and timeliness. Instant messaging is far superior to other methods.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Comparison Items</th><th>Flashduty</th><th>Pagerduty</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><strong>Does it provide Email support?</strong></td><td>✅</td><td>✅</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Is dedicated support available?</strong></td><td>✅, supports exclusive IM service groups</td><td>Needs to be purchased separately</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Is expert remote support available?</strong></td><td>✅, supports remote meetings to solve problems</td><td>Needs to be purchased separately</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Service Time</strong></td><td>Standard version: 5<em>8, Professional version: 7</em>8</td><td>Unknown</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Does it provide a Status Page?</strong></td><td>Yes, <a href="https://status.flashcat.cloud/">status.flashcat.cloud</a></td><td>Yes, <a href="https://status.pagerduty.com/">status.pagerduty.com</a></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Does it provide a Roadmap?</strong></td><td>Yes, <a href="https://c9xudyniiq.feishu.cn/base/SAUGbfgkeatk9Gsqjj0cH6eGnZg">roadmap.flashcat.cloud</a></td><td>No</td></tr></tbody></table><h3>Finally</h3><p>We recommend you look for a solution that can be customized to your needs and adapt to your different workflows. This largely depends on your satisfaction with the provider’s alerting and notification workflows, integrations, scheduling and escalations, pricing, and various other features. We suggest you choose after a comprehensive trial and evaluation.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>What Is an Incident</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/alter/what_is_incident.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: The incident in Flashduty represents an ongoing problem or a matter that needs to be addressed. An incident is generally triggered by an alert and is often associated with a series of similar alerts.</h2><h1>What Is an Incident</h1><p>An incident represents an ongoing problem or a matter that needs to be addressed. An incident is generally triggered by an alert and is often associated with a series of similar alerts.</p><h2>Incident, Alert, and Events</h2><p>When Flashduty receives an alert event (such as an alert notification from Zabbix), the system will automatically trigger an alert, and this alert will trigger an incident. Multiple similar active alerts may be aggregated into the same incident and dispatched, notified, and processed together.</p><p>We can simply understand it as: <strong>an incident is a combination of similar alerts</strong>. In the absence of noise reduction, an incident is equivalent to an alert. Conversely, in the case of noise reduction, an incident is equivalent to its associated multiple alerts. For more information on the noise reduction model of alerts, please read <a href="doc-4185939">Understanding the Noise Reduction Process</a>.</p><h2>Incident Severity, Status, and Progress</h2><h3>Severity</h3><ul><li><strong>Info</strong>: Minor, the service itself is still running normally, only a service status reminder is provided, and no immediate action is required.</li><li><strong>Warning</strong>: Warning, the service may be malfunctioning or problems are about to occur, and early intervention is recommended to prevent the issue from escalating.</li><li><strong>Critical</strong>: Severe, the service is experiencing widespread issues or is even interrupted, affecting users, and immediate intervention is required.</li></ul><p>Incidents, alerts, and events all use the above three severity levels. <strong>The severity level is capitalized</strong>, so you need to be careful when using the API. The severity generation rules for the three are as follows:</p><ul><li><strong>Event Severity</strong>: Alert events from different integration sources (such as Zabbix and Nightingale) have different severity enumeration values, and Flashduty will map them to the above three standard severity levels according to certain rules. For specific mapping relationships, please refer to the documentation for the specific integration.</li><li><strong>Alert Severity</strong>: Equal to the highest severity level of the associated event.</li><li><strong>Incident Severity</strong>: Equal to the highest severity level of the associated alerts.</li></ul><h3>Processing Progress</h3><ul><li><strong>Pending</strong>: After an incident is triggered, the processing progress defaults to &quot;Pending,&quot; and the system will initiate automatic dispatch, assign handlers, and notify them.</li><li><strong>In Progress</strong>: If any person clicks <strong>Claim Incident</strong>, the processing progress will immediately change to &quot;In Progress.&quot; In this case, the incident's handlers may be in <strong>Claimed</strong> or <strong>Unclaimed</strong> status, but at least one person is in &quot;Claimed&quot; status. When all handlers <strong>Unclaim</strong>, the incident processing progress will revert to &quot;Pending.&quot;</li><li><strong>Closed</strong>: If anyone clicks <strong>Close Incident</strong> or the incident <strong>Automatically Recovers</strong>, the processing progress will immediately change to &quot;Closed.&quot;</li></ul><h3>Incident Status</h3><p>The status of an alert represents the status of the incident in the original monitoring system, i.e., &quot;Recovered&quot; or &quot;Not Recovered.&quot; The status of an incident is entirely determined by its associated alerts.</p><ul><li><strong>Recovered</strong>: If all associated alerts have recovered, the incident will automatically recover.</li><li><strong>Not Recovered</strong>: If at least one of the associated alerts has not recovered, the incident will remain in a &quot;Not Recovered&quot; state.</li></ul><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
Automatic incident recovery will cause the (processing progress) to be automatically closed; however, manually closing an incident will have no impact on the incident's status.</p></blockquote><h2>Incident Tags</h2><p>Labels are a very important basic concept in Flashduty. Different labels describe alert and incident information in different dimensions, and are widely used in filtering, retrieval, aggregation and other scenarios.</p><p><strong>How Are Tags Generated?</strong></p><p>The tags of an alert are extracted from the event message body reported by the original alert system. Different sources have different extraction methods. Generally, we adopt the principle of <strong>extracting as much as possible</strong>. For example, for alerts from Prometheus, Flashduty will extract the Labels and Annotations information from the Payload.</p><p>Tags can only be obtained through event reporting and cannot be manually modified or added. The tags of an automatically triggered incident are always equal to the tags of its associated first alert. For a manually triggered incident, the tags will always be empty.</p><p>Flashduty provides a tag enhancement solution for automatically generating tags. Go to <a href="http://docs.flashcat.cloud/zh/flashduty/label-enrichment-settings">Configure Tag Enhancement</a> to learn more.</p><h2>Incident Lifecycle</h2><p><strong>1. Trigger a New Incident</strong></p><p><strong>Automatic Triggering</strong>: When Flashduty receives an alert event (such as a Zabbix notification) reported by an integration, the event automatically triggers an alert, and the alert automatically triggers an incident.</p><p><strong>Manual Triggering</strong>: Manually in the Flashduty console, click the <strong>Create Incident</strong> button, fill in the title, description, severity, and other information to trigger a new incident.</p><p><strong>2. Dispatch and Notification</strong></p><p>After a new incident is triggered, Flashduty will match the dispatch strategy under the associated collaboration space. After matching the dispatch strategy, the system will assign the incident to an individual, team member, or on-duty personnel and notify them. <strong>If no dispatch strategy is matched, the incident will not be assigned to anyone, and no notification will be given</strong>.</p><p>You can set different dispatch strategies for different time periods or different types of incidents to achieve flexible dispatch. The system allows you to set up multiple dispatch stages under one dispatch strategy. If the assigned personnel of the current stage do not complete the incident confirmation and processing within the specified time, the system will automatically escalate to the next stage. Escalation is equivalent to reassigning the incident to other personnel.</p><p>You can flexibly arrange notification methods in the dispatch strategy. Flashduty supports a large number of group chat and one-on-one notification channels. One-on-one is a one-to-one push channel (such as voice, text message, and email), and group chat is a push message to a message group (such as Feishu, DingTalk, and Slack), and provides additional reminders to assigned personnel.</p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
Note that <strong>an incident will only be notified after it is assigned</strong>. Without assignment, there will be no notifications.</p></blockquote><p>If you assign an incident to a duty schedule where no one is on call (a &quot;bye&quot; slot), the system will not send notifications to any individuals. However, if you have configured a group chat channel, messages will still be pushed to the group chat.</p><p><strong>3. Claim and Resolve</strong></p><p>On-call personnel can immediately claim the incident after receiving the notification. You can claim the incident in <strong>voice calls</strong> and <strong>instant messages</strong>. After claiming, the incident processing progress will change to <strong>In Progress</strong>.</p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
Flashduty currently does not restrict incidents to only being claimed by &quot;assigned handlers.&quot; Anyone who sees the incident can click to claim it.</p></blockquote><p><strong>Closing an Incident</strong> will cause the processing progress to change to <strong>Closed</strong>. If the incident's associated alerts automatically recover, the incident will also automatically close. Conversely, if you manually close the incident, it will cause all associated alerts to automatically close. This means that these alerts will not be merged into any new events.</p><h2>Incident Timeline</h2><p>Each incident has a timeline that is used to trace back the changes and operations that occurred at different moments in the incident's history. For example, at what point in time, through what channel, who was notified of the incident, and the results of the notification.</p><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/what_is_incident/1.avif" alt="" /></p><h2>Triggering an Incident</h2><h3>Triggering an Incident Through Integration</h3><p>Flashduty already supports most common monitoring systems, including Prometheus, Zabbix, Nightingale, and cloud monitoring, etc. Go to <a href="/mixin/alert_integration/nightingale">Alert Integration</a> to view specific operation steps.</p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
Flashduty supports dedicated integration and shared integration modes. Delivering the alert to the exclusive integration under the collaboration space will trigger the incident under this collaboration space.
Or deliver the alert to the shared integration in the integration center, and then configure routing to deliver the alert to different collaboration spaces according to rules.</p></blockquote><h3>Triggering an Incident via API</h3><p>Flashduty provides a custom event standard that allows you to report alerts through standard protocols, suitable for any unadapted monitoring system. Please read <a href="/mixin/alert_integration/custom_alert">Custom Events</a> for detailed documentation.</p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
To ensure the stability of the entire system, Flashduty currently has a <strong>200qps</strong> frequency limit for API reporting. If the limit is exceeded, reporting will be refused.</p></blockquote><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
Please ensure that you will actively close the alert, or set the incident to automatically close after a timeout in the collaboration space. When there are too many incidents, console retrieval performance will drop sharply. At that time, the system may close historical incidents without any notification.</p></blockquote><h3>Triggering an Incident via Email</h3><p>Flashduty provides an email integration that allows you to report alerts by sending an email, suitable for all monitoring systems that support email notifications. Please read <a href="/mixin/alert_integration/email">Custom Events</a> for detailed documentation.</p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
You can set specific email prefixes for each integration. You can also contact us to set an exclusive domain name for your main account that is easy to remember. For example, <a href="mailto:order-service@tesla.flashcat.cloud">order-service@tesla.flashcat.cloud</a>.</p></blockquote><h3>Triggering an Incident via the Console</h3><p>Click the <strong>Create</strong> button on the console to initiate incident creation.</p><table><thead><tr><th align="center">Type</th><th align="center">Is it Required</th><th>Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center">Incident title</td><td align="center">Trigger time, Unix timestamp</td><td>A brief statement of what happened</td></tr><tr><td align="center">Incident Description</td><td align="center">No</td><td>A detailed description of the incident, supporting Markdown syntax</td></tr><tr><td align="center">Severity</td><td align="center">Trigger time, Unix timestamp</td><td>Select one of the three enumeration values: Critical, Warning, Info</td></tr><tr><td align="center">Collaborative Space</td><td align="center">No</td><td>The incident's归属<br>If not selected, it represents a global incident.<br>In this case, the incident must be directly assigned to a person to notify</td></tr><tr><td align="center">Assigned Personnel</td><td align="center">No</td><td>The incident's handler<br>If not selected, it will be matched and assigned according to the collaboration space it belongs to.<br>Otherwise, notifications will be made directly according to personal preferences</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></description></item><item><title>Search and view incidents</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/alter/view_incidents.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Understand the use of incident lists and detail pages, including aggregate views, filtering, and timelines</h2><h1>Search and view incidents</h1><p>Connect all alert events of the company to Flashduty to view and process alerts in a centralized manner.</p><h2>Incident List</h2><p>Flashduty provides two entrances to view the incident list. One is within the collaboration space, and the other is under the incident management menu. The difference is that under the Incident management menu, you can see incidents from multiple collaboration spaces, or even all incidents in the company.</p><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/view_incidents/1.avif" alt="" /></p><ol><li><strong>Assigned Personnel</strong>: By default, the focus is on incidents <strong>assigned to me</strong>. You can switch to view incidents under the entire account.</li><li><strong>Processing Progress</strong>: Filter incidents by processing progress. The default is <strong>all</strong>.</li><li><strong>Time Filtering</strong>: Supports relative time and custom interval filtering. Note that for query performance, <strong>the start and end time of the query must not exceed 1 month</strong>. If you want to query data from more than a month ago, adjust the start and end times accordingly.</li><li><strong>Type Search</strong>: Supports searching by incident ID. If the assignee is set to &quot;assigned to me,&quot; it also supports fuzzy matching of &quot;Incident title.&quot;</li><li><strong>Frequently Used Filters</strong>: Supports saving high-frequency filtering conditions, such as &quot;My Collaboration Space,&quot; as &quot;Frequently Used Filters&quot; to speed up daily processing efficiency.</li><li><strong>More Filters</strong>: Supports rich dimension filters, including severity, labels, or custom fields.</li><li><strong>View Settings</strong>: Supports various rendering forms, including the introduction of <strong>custom display attributes</strong> and even aggregate views.</li><li><strong>Pagination Settings</strong>: Adjust pagination and the number of items per page.</li></ol><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
To improve performance, when search conditions match more than <strong>1000</strong> incidents, the system only displays 1000+ instead of the exact number. Therefore, you can only view 1000 incidents by navigating through pages. If you need to view more, please adjust your search time interval. Or use the <a href="https://developer.flashcat.cloud/api-110655782">Incident Query</a> API to get all data.</p></blockquote><h3>Using Aggregate Views</h3><p>Aggregate views provide a different perspective on incidents, allowing you to define different aggregation dimensions. The essence of aggregation dimensions is real-time Group By, such as aggregating by severity.</p><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/view_incidents/2.avif" alt="" /></p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
To improve performance, in the aggregate view, the system can match up to <strong>100</strong> pieces of data for aggregation. Therefore, the list page you see may not contain all matching data. If this is a concern, switch to list view.</p></blockquote><h3>Using More Filters</h3><p>Flashduty provides filtering capabilities across various dimensions and gives you ample flexibility. The most typical scenarios are:</p><ul><li>Retrieving incidents triggered by the alert policy &quot;Host Down&quot; based on the check tag.</li><li>Retrieving incidents marked as &quot;false positives&quot; based on the false positive field.</li></ul><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
Flexibility often means lower performance, and this is no exception in Flashduty, despite our extensive performance optimization efforts. We always recommend narrowing your time query range and using conditions like <strong>assigned to me</strong> and <strong>processing progress</strong> to reduce the query scope.</p></blockquote><h3>Custom Rendering</h3><p>Under the <strong>Settings</strong> tab, select or turn off the display of the following content to customize the incident list:</p><ol><li><strong>Basic Attributes</strong>: Define whether to display basic information such as duration and processing personnel.</li><li><strong>Custom Fields</strong>: You can select custom fields defined by the platform. If an incident has not set this field, it will display &quot; - &quot;.</li><li><strong>Tags</strong>: You can filter and select tags. If an incident does not have this tag, it will display &quot; - &quot;.</li></ol><h2>Incident Details</h2><p>Incident details are the main entry point for investigating incidents, displaying all the information we can gather. Especially on the incident overview page, Flashduty focuses on the information you need most.</p><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/view_incidents/3.avif" alt="" /></p><ol><li><strong>Key Information</strong>: Incident title, severity, processing progress, ID number, collaboration space, duration, etc.</li><li><strong>Details</strong>: Incident description, impact, and tags. The description and impact support Markdown.</li><li><strong>Operation Area</strong>: Various high-frequency operation buttons, including custom and low-frequency operation buttons.</li><li><strong>Dispatch Information</strong>: Current processing personnel information and dispatch method. If a strategy dispatch is used and there is a next step, the upgrade countdown will be displayed here.</li><li><strong>Custom Fields</strong>: Custom field configuration area.</li></ol><p>You can switch to the above tabs to view more detailed <strong>associated alerts</strong>, <strong>timelines</strong>, and <strong>historical changes</strong> for incident root cause analysis. For closed incidents, the system will also display the <strong>problem resolution</strong> page to show the root cause and solution of the incident.</p><h3>Frequently Asked Questions</h3><p>|+| Console Error: Due to the large volume of data, we are unable to respond to your request in a timely manner...</p><pre><code>This error often appears on incident, alert list query, and analysis dashboard pages. It is mainly due to the system matching too much data, causing the query to time out.

In this case, please narrow the query scope, such as the time interval, or use precise query conditions. If you still have issues, please contact us.
</code></pre>]]></description></item><item><title>Handling and Updating Incidents</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/alter/edit_incidents.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Learn how to modify the title and other information of an incident, and how to handle the incident</h2><h1>Handling and Updating Incidents</h1><p>Investigate incidents, update key information, and synchronize the situation with others.</p><h2>Modify Information</h2><p>When an incident is triggered, and the problem manifestation becomes clearer over time, you can modify the incident's title and other key information to make it more accurate than the original alert information.</p><h3>Modify Incident Title</h3><ol><li>Click on the incident details in the console, and in the title section, click the Modify button.</li><li>Enter a new title and you're done.</li></ol><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
The modified title will not change with the incorporation of new alerts.</p></blockquote><h3>Modify Incident Severity</h3><ol><li>Click on the incident details in the console, and in the severity section, select a new severity level.</li><li>Once the mouse loses focus, the change is complete.</li></ol><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
The modified severity will not change with the incorporation of new alerts.</p></blockquote><h3>Modify Incident Description and Impact</h3><ol><li>Click on the incident details in the console, and in the description and impact section, click to directly input new information.</li><li>The system will save it automatically.</li></ol><p><strong>You can use Markdown syntax to update the description and impact of the incident, or you can directly copy and paste images!</strong></p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
The modified description will not change with the incorporation of new alerts.</p></blockquote><h2>Claim the Incident</h2><p>You have three ways to claim a newly triggered incident.</p><h3>Claim the Incident Through the Console</h3><ul><li><strong>Single Claim</strong>: In the console, click on the incident details, and click the <strong>Claim</strong> button to complete the claim.</li><li><strong>Batch Operation</strong>: In the console incident list, select multiple incidents to be processed, and click the <strong>Claim</strong> button to complete the batch claim.</li></ul><h3>Claim the Incident Through the IM Application</h3><ul><li><strong>Application Messages</strong>: The main card of application messages provides a <strong>Claim</strong> button. Click the card to complete the claim. If nothing happens when you click on the card, it may be that you have not completed the login account association within the app or for other reasons. For details, please refer to <a href="http://docs.flashcat.cloud/zh/flashduty/lark-integration-guide">Feishu Lark Integration Guide</a>.</li><li><strong>Robot Messages</strong>: Most robot channels push messages in Markdown format. You can modify the notification template and add a <strong>Claim</strong> jump link to redirect to the console for claiming. For details, please refer to the default template.</li></ul><h3>Claim the Incident via Voice Call</h3><p>Flashduty's voice alerts, at the end of the voice broadcast, will remind you to <strong>press 1 to claim it with one click</strong>. Press button 1, and the system will complete the incident claim on your behalf.</p><h3>Unclaim the Incident</h3><p>Once someone claims an incident, the incident's processing progress will change from &quot;Pending&quot; to &quot;Closed.&quot; Other people claiming the incident will not change the processing progress.</p><p>After one person claims an incident, they can choose to <strong>Unclaim</strong> it, which is useful in case of a mistaken claim. When all claimed individuals cancel their claims, the incident will revert to the <strong>Pending</strong> state.</p><h3>Processing Progress and MTTA</h3><p>You can view each person's dispatch time and claim time in the console. We calculate the incident's MTTA according to the following rules:</p><ul><li>MTTA (Mean Time to Acknowledge) is defined as the average time to claim, i.e., the average difference between the claim time and the trigger time.</li><li>For the same incident, each person can have different dispatch times and claim times. Therefore, for an incident, the MTTA calculation difference varies for each person.</li><li>For the overall MTTA of an incident, only the difference between the incident's trigger time and the time of the first claim is calculated.</li></ul><h2>Suspend Processing</h2><p>The handler of an incident, after claiming it, may need some time to investigate and process the incident. The <strong>Suspend</strong> operation can temporarily stop the incident from escalating according to the expected dispatch strategy. After claiming the incident, you can set a suspension time, such as 2 hours, 4 hours, or a custom expiration time within 24 hours.</p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
If you have already suspended the incident, and the suspension time has expired, and you still have not completed the incident's processing, the system will automatically revert the incident to the <strong>Pending</strong> state and re-initiate the dispatch notification.</p></blockquote><h3>Suspend Incident via Console</h3><p>Click on the incident details in the console, click the <strong>Suspend</strong> button, select the suspension duration, and complete.</p><h3>Suspend Incident via IM Application</h3><p>Click the <strong>Suspend</strong> button on the incident message card, select the suspension duration, and complete.</p><h2>Close Incident</h2><p>You have multiple ways to close an incident.</p><h3>Close Incident via Console</h3><ul><li><strong>Single Close</strong>: In the console, click on the incident details, and click the <strong>Close</strong> button to complete the closure.</li><li><strong>Batch Operation</strong>: In the console incident list, select multiple incidents to be processed, and click the <strong>Close</strong> button to complete the batch closure.</li></ul><h3>Close Incident via IM Application</h3><p>The main card of application messages provides a <strong>Close</strong> button. Click the card to complete the closure. If nothing happens when you click on the card, it may be that you have not completed the login account association within the app or for other reasons. For details, please refer to <a href="http://docs.flashcat.cloud/zh/flashduty/lark-integration-guide">Feishu Lark Integration Guide</a>.</p><h3>Reopen Incident</h3><p>Manually closing an incident will change its processing progress to <strong>Closed</strong>. You can click the <strong>Close</strong> button in any state. After an incident is manually closed, its associated alerts will also stop incorporating new events. If the alert in the original alert system has not recovered, new notification events may be generated, which will trigger new alerts and incidents in Flashduty.</p><p>You can reopen an incident after accidentally closing it. After reopening, the incident will revert to the <strong>Pending</strong> state, and dispatches and notifications will be re-initiated.</p><h2>Merge Processing</h2><p>You can manually merge between incidents or between incidents and alerts. Merging similar alerts and incidents together can converge information into the same incident and speed up the processing process.</p><p><strong>Merge Between Incidents</strong>: In the console, you can select multiple incidents and merge them into one target incident. You can also merge at a certain location in the incident details by selecting another target incident.</p><p><strong>Merge Alert into Incident</strong>: Alerts that are merged into an incident due to aggregation policies can be adjusted. You can go to the alert details and click the <strong>Merge</strong> button to migrate the alert to the target incident.</p><p><strong>The essence of merging is: changing the relationship between alerts and incidents. If all alerts associated with an incident are merged into another incident, this incident will be closed directly, and you only need to handle the target incident later.</strong></p><p>A complete timeline will fully record your modification process.</p><h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2><p>|+| I suspended the incident. Why does the system still trigger a new similar incident?</p><pre><code>You may have misunderstood the **Suspend** function as the **Silence** function, but there is a significant difference between the two.

- The silent function requires you to fill in the matching policy. When a newly triggered incident matches the silent policy, no notification will be issued. The silent policy can affect the trigger notification of new incidents.
- The suspension function does not require you to fill in any policies. It only buys you a period of time to process the incident after you claim the incident, preventing the incident from being escalated to the next handler during the processing process.

If you need to block an alert policy, use **Silence** instead of **Suspend**.
</code></pre>]]></description></item><item><title>Upgrading and Dispatching Incidents</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/alter/escalate_incidents.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Learn how to reassign, upgrade an assignment, or add a handler</h2><h1>Upgrading and Dispatching Incidents</h1><p>Reassign, upgrade the assignment, or add a handler.</p><h2>Reassign</h2><p>When an incident is assigned to you, but you confirm that you are not the correct assignee, or you are unable to handle the incident, you can choose to reassign the incident to another person or duty schedule.</p><p>Reassigning means re-notifying. If an incident in <strong>processing</strong> is reassigned, the incident's processing progress may be reset to <strong>pending</strong>. Unless the new handler includes the previous handler, and the previous handler has already claimed the incident.</p><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
Currently, the target of reassignment can only be a duty schedule or an individual, which we call <strong>direct assignment</strong>. The difference from <strong>policy-based assignment</strong> is that directly assigned incidents can only be notified according to personal preferences, and there is no possibility of upgrade.</p></blockquote><h2>Upgrade Dispatch</h2><ul><li><p><strong>Automatic Upgrade</strong>: When an incident is automatically assigned to you according to a (multi-stage) assignment policy, and you do not resolve the incident within the specified time window, do not choose to postpone the upgrade, and the incident does not automatically recover, the incident will automatically upgrade to the next stage at the specified time.</p></li><li><p><strong>Manual Upgrade</strong>: When an incident is automatically assigned to you according to a (multi-stage) assignment policy, but after receiving the alert, you confirm that you cannot handle the incident and need the next stage (such as second-line technical support) to intervene, you can choose to directly upgrade the assignment of the incident to another stage.</p></li></ul><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
The essence of upgrading the assignment is <strong>reassignment</strong>. The main difference is that <strong>upgrading the assignment</strong> dispatches and notifies according to the personnel and notification channels that have been set in the assignment policy.</p></blockquote><h2>Add Handler</h2><p>When an incident is assigned to you, but you need another person (who is not among the current handlers) to participate in handling it, you can choose to add a handler.</p><p>Similar to <strong>reassignment</strong>, when adding a handler, you can only select a duty schedule or an individual as the assignment target. The system will notify these individuals based on their personal preferences.</p><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/escalate_incidents/1.avif" alt="" /></p><h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2><p>|+| Why is there no policy-based notification when adding handlers?</p><pre><code>Adding handlers and reassigning are set according to personal notification preferences by default, and you can update them on the personal settings page. In the future, we will support modifying the notification method independently when dispatching.
</code></pre><p>|+| Why is there no upgrade button in my incident details?</p><pre><code>You can switch between different dispatch stages only when the incident is dispatched according to a dispatch policy. When you choose direct assignment (such as reassigning to an individual), the incident is not associated with any assignment policy and cannot be upgraded through the policy.
</code></pre>]]></description></item><item><title>Custom Fields</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/alter/custom_fields.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Understand, configure, and use custom fields</h2><h1>Custom Fields</h1><p>Understand, configure, and use custom fields.</p><h2>Usage Scenarios</h2><p>FlashDuty has integrated with most common alert systems, and we have placed most of the information from the push content into Labels for display. However, our users still have some expansion or customization needs, such as manually marking an incident as a false positive. Therefore, we provide the <strong>custom fields</strong> feature to further enrich incident descriptions.</p><p>With custom fields, you can add custom metadata, record specific incident-related information, and pass and use this information during incident processing. The following are common usage scenarios for custom fields:</p><ul><li><strong>Flexible Definition</strong>: You can create multiple custom fields as needed and define the field names, types, options, and default values. Common custom field types include text, drop-down lists, and checkboxes.</li></ul><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/custom_fields/1.avif" alt="" /></p><ul><li><strong>Information Association</strong>: Through custom fields, you can associate incidents with other related data. For example, you can add custom fields to identify affected systems, geographic locations, associated customers, or whether it is a false positive.</li></ul><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/custom_fields/2.avif" alt="" /></p><ul><li><strong>Filtering and Categorization</strong>: The incident list supports filtering and categorizing views based on custom fields. You can create common filters based on the values of custom fields to better organize and handle incidents.</li></ul><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/custom_fields/3.avif" alt="" /></p><h2>Configure Custom Fields</h2><h3>Create Fields</h3><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
An account supports the creation of up to 15 custom fields.</p></blockquote><ol><li><p>Enter the console <strong>Incident Management =&gt; Custom Fields</strong></p></li><li><p>Click <strong>Create Custom Field</strong></p></li><li><p>Enter the following information:</p><p><strong>Field Name</strong>: Identifies the field in the API; cannot be modified after creation.
<strong>Display Name</strong>: The field displayed in the incident details page; can be modified after creation.
<strong>Field Description</strong>: Assists incident handlers in understanding and using the field.</p></li><li><p>Select the field type and add options and default values as needed. Field types include:</p><p><strong>Text</strong>: Plain text input box, up to 500 characters.
<strong>Single Select</strong>: Single-selection drop-down box, allowing up to ten options, each not exceeding 200 characters.
<strong>Multi-Select</strong>: Multi-selection drop-down box, allowing up to ten options, each not exceeding 200 characters.
<strong>Checkbox</strong>: Checkbox.</p></li><li><p>Click <strong>Submit</strong> to complete</p></li></ol><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
If a field has a default value set, the system will automatically write the field and assign the default value when the incident is generated. Note that the field only affects new incidents and has no impact on existing incidents.</p></blockquote><h3>Update Fields</h3><p>Only the following content can be updated:</p><ol><li>Display Name</li><li>Field Description</li><li>Field Options (for single-select and multi-select types only)</li><li>Default Value</li></ol><blockquote><p>[!TIP]
After the field is updated, it only affects new incidents and has no impact on existing incidents.</p></blockquote><h3>Delete Fields</h3><p>You can initiate a deletion operation in the console at any time. However, please note that deletion is a time-consuming operation. When a field is deleted, the system will scan historical incidents and update asynchronously to remove the association between the field and the incident. You cannot re-create a field with the same name until the deletion is complete.</p><h2>Frequently Asked Questions</h2><p>|+| Why can't I search for incidents using the field I created?</p><pre><code>Please confirm whether the field type you want to search is **text** type. To ensure system stability, the system currently does not support searching for text type fields. Please understand.
</code></pre>]]></description></item><item><title>Custom Actions</title><link>https://doc.flashduty.com/en/flashduty/alter/custom_actions.htm</link><pubDate>2024-11-07T07:50:31</pubDate><description><![CDATA[<hr /><h2>brief: Understand the usage scenarios and configuration methods of custom actions</h2><h1>Custom Actions</h1><h2>Usage Scenarios</h2><p>A custom action is a Webhook call. You can add custom actions for incidents in different collaboration spaces and manually trigger the action in the incident details to achieve rapid troubleshooting or information synchronization.</p><p>Common usage scenarios for custom actions:</p><ol><li><strong>Restart the host</strong>: When the host memory or CPU is full, trigger the host restart script to quickly complete the host restart.</li><li><strong>Rich information</strong>: When an incident occurs, call back your service, retrieve Tracing, Logging, topology, and other information according to the alert details, and actively call the FlashDuty Open API to update the incident information, such as adding labels or setting custom fields to assist in troubleshooting.</li><li><strong>Rollback changes</strong>: When an incident occurs, if it is determined that the incident is caused by a change, you can directly trigger a callback to your deployment platform, start the rollback process, and speed up incident recovery.</li><li><strong>Update Status Page</strong>: When it is determined that the incident affects online services, you can trigger an update to the external Status Page to notify your customers or upstream and downstream users in a timely manner.</li></ol><h2>Configure Custom Actions</h2><ol><li>Log in to the console and go to <strong>Integration Center =&gt; Webhook</strong></li><li>Click <strong>Add Custom Action</strong> Integration</li><li>Configure the following information:</li></ol><ul><li><strong>Action Name</strong>: This name will be displayed as a button in the incident details.</li><li><strong>Collaboration Spaces</strong>: You can configure multiple spaces, but each space can have up to three custom actions.</li><li><strong>Endpoint</strong>: The HTTP(s) address that will be triggered when the custom action button is clicked.</li><li><strong>Custom Headers</strong>: The custom message headers to be included when requesting the endpoint.</li></ul><ol start="4"><li>Save and complete</li></ol><p>After creation, you can see the operation button under [Incident Details - More Operations] in the corresponding space. Click the button and the system will prompt you with the operation result. If the operation is successful, the system will write the operation record.</p><p><img src="https://fc.3ti.site/zh/flashduty/alter/custom_actions/1.avif" alt="" /></p><h3>How to Implement a Webhook?</h3><p>Go to <a href="https://developer.flashcat.cloud/doc-2996930">Webhook Get Started</a> to learn more.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>